<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>international meeting on Meixin Zhu</title>
    <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/tags/international-meeting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in international meeting on Meixin Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Meixin Zhu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://MeixinZhu.github.io/tags/international-meeting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the 97th Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/trb2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/trb2018/</guid>
      <description>The Transportation Research Board (TRB) 97th Annual Meeting was held January 7–11, 2018, at the Walter E. Washington Convention Center, in Washington, D.C. The information-packed program attracted more than 13,000 transportation professionals from around the world.
The meeting program covered all transportation modes, with more than 5,000 presentations in nearly 800 sessions and workshops, addressing topics of interest to policy makers, administrators, practitioners, researchers, and representatives of government, industry, and academic institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Fifth International Symposium on Transportation Safety</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/safety/</guid>
      <description>During September 25 and 26, 2017, the Fifth International Symposium on Transportation Safety was held at Tongji University. The symposium was jointly held by Tongji University, Traffic Management Research Institute of the Ministry of Public Security, and the Research Institute of Highway of the Ministry of Transport. Zhu served as a volunteer for the meeting organizing.   A group photo of attendees   Background Traffic crashes have caused about 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the 96th Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/trb2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/trb2017/</guid>
      <description>The 96th Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board (TRB) was held on January 8 – 12 2017, at the Walter E. Washington Convention Center, in Washington, D.C. – USA. The spotlight theme for the 2017 TRB Annual Meeting is Transportation Innovation: Leading the Way in an Era of Rapid Change. The program attracted more than 12,000 transportation professionals from around the world to Washington, D.C.
Meixin Zhu gave an oral presentation on car-following model calibration and validation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the 5th International Symposium on Naturalistic Driving Research in Blacksburg, Virginia</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/nds-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/nds-symposium/</guid>
      <description>The National Surface Transportation Safety Center for Excellence (NSTSCE) at Virginia Tech Transportation Institute (VTTI) hosted the Fifth International Symposium on Naturalistic Driving Research at The Inn at Virginia Tech and Skelton Conference Center in Blacksburg, Virginia on August 30-31, 2016, with the Motorcycle Research and Technology Workshop and Women in Transportation Seminar – The Future of Transportation following on September 1.
The symposium provided researchers and practitioners with an overview of international naturalistic driving studies, a method designed to track driver behavior in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the 16th COTA International Conference of Transportation Professionals</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/cictp-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/post/cictp-2016/</guid>
      <description>The 16th COTA International Conference of Transportation Professionals (CICTP2016) was held during July 6-9, 2016, in Shanghai, China, jointly organized by Shanghai Maritime University (SMU) and Chinese Overseas Transportation Association (COTA).
CICTP2016 attracted more than 700 participants domestically and internationally, who came from mainland China, the United States of America, United Arab Emirates, Hong Kong, Taiwan, Greece, Singapore, Australia, United Kingdom, Germany, Korea, Belgium, Switzerland and New Zealand. Nearly thirty conference sessions such as plenary, spotlight, honored invited, and technical sessions, as well as special forums were organized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>