<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Meixin Zhu</title>
    <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Meixin Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Meixin Zhu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shanghai Naturalistic Driving Study</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/sh-nds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/sh-nds/</guid>
      <description>Work Summary  Collected 60 Chinese drivers’ real-world driving data, with a total mileage of 161,055 km. Investigated decision-making mechanisms for essential driving behaviors based on 108,933 car-following events, 17,309 lane-change events, 7,845 cut-in events, and 3,256 vehicle-pedestrian conflicts. Calibrated, validated, and cross-compared five representative car-following models and found that the full velocity difference model performed best for Shanghai drivers. Investigated the impact of a forward collision warning system on drivers’ car following behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlphaDrive: Mastering Driving with Real-World Driving Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/alphadrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/alphadrive/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on developing AlphaDrive, a platform equipped with real-world driving scenarios where intelligent agents can learn to drive by trial and error, trials and errors that number in the billions. The platform is comprised of three main modules:
 Driving Scenario Database: containing typical driving scenarios (e.g., car following, lane changing, overtaking, and vehicle-pedestrian conflicts) extracted from naturalistic driving studies or field operation test databases. Microscopic Traffic Simulator: loading driving scenarios, executing given driving policies and returning their performance indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving Behavior Research for Intelligent Collision Avoidance Technology</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/faw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/faw/</guid>
      <description>Work Summary  Examined the effects of situational urgency on drivers’ collision avoidance behaviors using Tongji University&amp;rsquo;s eight-degree-of-freedom driving simulator. Developed a kinematic-based forward collision warning (FCW) algorithm that is compatible with drivers’ risk perceptions and behavioral responses. Implemented the proposed FCW algorithm in Tongji University driving simulator, and evaluated the system&amp;rsquo;s performance, warning timing, and safety benefits.  Introduction Driving Behavior Research for Intelligent Collision Avoidance Technology is a driving simulator study jointly conducted by Tongji University and China First Automobile Work (FAW) Corporation (one of the largest automobile companies in China).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udacity Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/nano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/nano/</guid>
      <description>Udacity, partnered with the best companies in the autonomous driving field, offered a Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Program. I have actively participated in the program and here are the projects I have finished.   Interesting projects in Udacity Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Program   In this program, I have grasped essential knowledge in deep learning, computer vision, sensor fusion, localization, controllers, vehicle kinematics, automotive hardware for autonomous driving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Car Following by Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/rlcar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/rlcar/</guid>
      <description>This on-going project aims to develop autonomous car-following strategies based on deep Reinforcement Learning (deep RL).
Deep Reinforcement Learning Deep RL is a field that seeks to combine the advances in deep neural networks with reinforcement learning algorithms to create agents capable of acting intelligently in complex environments, and exciting breakthroughs have been witnessed, like deep Q-network and AlphaGo.
Deep reinforcement learning can achieve better generalization capability because it learns decision-making mechanisms from training data rather than parameter estimation through fitting the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End Learning for Steering Control</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/steer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/steer/</guid>
      <description>This on-going project is inspired by NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s research (1) and MIT 6.S094&amp;rsquo;s DeepTesla project (2). It aims to learn human drivers&amp;rsquo; strategy in steering control. The learned model can map raw pixels from a single front-facing camera directly to steering commands.
The training data includes image frames from a front-facing camera and the corresponding steering angles from human drivers. I started with the model described in Nvidia paper (1) and the following figure shows the initial results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Like Driving by Inverse Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/irl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/irl/</guid>
      <description>This on-going project is inspired by Levine et al. (2012). It aims to imitate human driving patterns. The rationale is that as long as other agents are human, autonomous vehicles should adopt “human-like” driving skills.
The assumption is that drivers act based on a utility (reward) function, which represents the preference of the driver and elicits the driving behavior. The role of inverse reinforcement learning (IRL) is to infer or discover the latent utility function from driver (expert) demonstrations and thus generalize the driving policy to unobserved situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Segmentation Based on Subspace Clustering</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/subspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/subspace/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed to segment different moving objects in a video sequence, using subspace clustering methods.
Subspace Clustering Introduction Clustering refers to techniques that find a low-dimensional representation of a high-dimensional data set. Conventional techniques, such as principal component analysis (PCA), assume that the data are drawn from a single low-dimensional subspace of a high-dimensional space. Such approaches have found widespread applications in many fields, e.g., pattern recognition, data compression, image processing, and bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Parameter Analysis Platform based on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/uav/</guid>
      <description>This project was for the 2014 National Competition of Transport Science and Technology for Students in China. It aimed to extract real-time traffic flow parameters, including volume, density, and intersection delay, etc., based on videos captured by an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV).
Video Capturing Equipment The project used a quad-rotor unmanned aerial vehicle to capture real-time traffic flow video. Its flight height ranged from 60 to 80 meters.   A quad-rotor unmanned aerial vehicle used to capture real-time traffic flow video   Video Stabilization A video stabilization method based on image-feature extraction and matching was developed to address the jitters produced by the UAV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Simulation based on Cellular Automaton Method</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/cell/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed to model the keep-right-except-to-pass rule using Cellular Automata (CA).
Cellular automaton system is a discrete dynamic system consisting of a regular grid of cells, each in one of a finite number of states. And the state of each cell is updated every single discrete time step according to the updating rules, which are determined by the current state of the cell and the states of its neighbor cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Design for Combined Road Alignment</title>
      <link>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://MeixinZhu.github.io/project/design/</guid>
      <description>Combined horizontal and vertical alignments are frequently used in mountainous freeways in China; however, design guidelines that consider the safety impact of combined alignments are not currently available. This project aims to estimate the effects of combined alignments on driving behavior (e.g., speed and lateral acceleration) and safety performance (crash surrogate measures like lane departure events and emergency braking events) using a driving simulator and field data. The results will assist engineers to design safer mountainous freeways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>